we said that we will explain why we need
a better predictor in two ways this was
one way the cpi gets a lot better the
other way
will be to see
how much waste there is
from amy's prediction so in a five-stage
pipeline what's happening really we have
three stages
that are relevant the one where we
resolve the branches and then we have to
destroy two instructions that we have
fetched if this branch has been
mispredicted so a misprediction costs us
two instructions here
in a deeper pipeline what happens is we
have our branch and for 10 cycles we
have been fetching things so a
misprediction now costs us 10
instructions
worth of work and that means that
avoiding mispredictions becomes more
important and finally when we have a
four instruction per cycle processor
that resolves branches in the 11th stage
after we have fetched this branch we
have fetched a lot of instructions after
we fetched the branch we fetched four
instructions in the next cycle and four
instructions in the next cycle so now
when we mispredict the branch we waste
40 instructions
that we could have done if the
prediction was correct so the cost of a
misprediction is much higher in terms of
instructions that we have just wasted
and that means that again it's much more
important to predict branches correctly